<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Andrea Ciceri</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Andrea Ciceri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 22:27:25 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Zen and the art of the Unix hacking</title><link>/posts/unix-zen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2017 22:27:25 +0100</pubDate><guid>/posts/unix-zen/</guid><description>More than two months are passed since my last post, I had some good ideas I would have liked to transform into posts but I&amp;rsquo;m afraid to be too lazy (in my defence I have to say that I&amp;rsquo;ve been really busy). However, maybe because I bought a new mechanical keyboard, maybe because I&amp;rsquo;m going to assemble a new pc for Christmas; this is a new post.
As I preannunced, since I&amp;rsquo;m building a new pc, I don&amp;rsquo;t want to switch on my new computer for the first time without knowing which software to install, so the purpose of this post is to provide a recipe with my favorite softwares (and their configurations).</description></item><item><title>SCMRL (SCheMeRogueLike)</title><link>/posts/scmrl/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 23:39:53 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/scmrl/</guid><description>Welcome to SCMRL (SCheMeRogueLike, yes I&amp;rsquo;ve to choose a more imaginative name), in this page I will collect the information about this my project.
2017/09/11 SCMRL is here on GitHub. This is the first commit, I worked on it at the end of July and I decided to upload it only now. The game is not playable but I feared that it could be accidentally deleted so here it is.</description></item><item><title>Vintage tetris written in Guile Scheme</title><link>/posts/tetris/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2017 15:15:02 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/tetris/</guid><description>This isn&amp;rsquo;t really recent but it worths to be mentionated on this site, about one month ago I started reading the Wizard book and I became obsessed with this fantastic language. The first real project I tried was this Tetris implementation using Guile (yep, his sanctity Stallman should be proud of me), the code was is orrible but it allowed me to discover how to make things working pratically. The SICP is a great book but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t offer any real world example.</description></item><item><title>Consonno</title><link>/posts/consonno/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 18:33:25 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/consonno/</guid><description>A bunch of photos of my trip to the ghost town Consonno.
I&amp;rsquo;ve used a Canon 600D with the default 18-135mm lense, the photos were taken in raw mode and then processed using RawTherapee, an open source software I really appreciate.</description></item><item><title>Carousel</title><link>/posts/test-post/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Jul 2017 20:39:39 +0200</pubDate><guid>/posts/test-post/</guid><description>Welcome to this fantastic testing post, let&amp;rsquo;s start a carousel of functionalities:
You can create links implicitly, e.g. https://www.fsf.org/ or foo@bar.org. Otherwise there is the traditional way, i.e this.
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to write in italic, in bold and in bold and italic, you can also strike the text.
But remember the koan:
A monk asked Zhaozhou Congshen, a Chinese Zen master: &amp;ldquo;Has a dog Buddha-nature or not?&amp;rdquo; Zhaozhou answered, &amp;ldquo;Mu&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>This is a personal site containing nothing interesting, there isn&amp;rsquo;t a main topic; I&amp;rsquo;ll simply upload anything that I want keep track of. The site is generated with Hugo, a cool static site generator, I realized this minimal theme using this pre-existing theme and Skeleton, a barebones CSS framework (yep I&amp;rsquo;m really funny).
This site is simple for two three reasons:
the less features I implement the less feature I have to repair when something broke I&amp;rsquo;m a lazy man (ok, maybe this reason would be enough) Using Vim to write these posts is fantastic&amp;hellip; Ah, another thing: I&amp;rsquo;m not a native english speaker, so be clement please.</description></item></channel></rss>